const quizQuestions6en = [
    {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting the electrode type for GTAW/TIG?",
    answers: ["Arc length.",
    "Base metal type.",
    "Welding technique (pulling/backhand or pushing/forehand).",
    "Welding torch size."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting the electrode type for GTAW/TIG?",
    answers: ["Current type (AC or DC).",
    "Arc length.",
    "Welding technique (pulling/backhand or pushing/forehand).",
    "Welding torch size."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting the electrode diameter for GTAW/TIG?",
    answers: ["Current type (AC or DC).",
    "Arc length.",
    "Welding technique (pulling/backhand or pushing/forehand).",
    "Base metal thickness."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting a nozzle size for the GTAW/TIG torch?",
    answers: ["Current type (AC or DC).",
    "Arc length.",
    "Welding technique (pulling/backhand or pushing/forehand).",
    "Base metal thickness."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting a nozzle size for the GTAW/TIG torch?",
    answers: ["Current type (AC or DC).",
    "Arc length.",
    "Welding technique (pulling/backhand or pushing/forehand).",
    "Welding current value."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting a nozzle size for the GTAW/TIG torch?",
    answers: ["Current type (AC or DC).",
    "Arc length.",
    "Welding technique (pulling/backhand or pushing/forehand).",
    "Tungsten electrode diameter."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting a gas flow rate for the GTAW/TIG process?",
    answers: ["Current type (AC or DC).",
    "Welding current polarity.",
    "Welding technique (pulling/backhand or pushing/forehand).",
    "Welding current value."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"For which of the following GTAW/TIG welding applications might a green-coded electrode be most appropriate?",
    answers: ["DCEP polarity for carbon steel.",
    "DCEN polarity for magnesium.",
    "High frequency AC arc striking for stainless steel.",
    "Alternating current for welding aluminium."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which process below is the most recommended for gouging root passes?",
    answers: ["Basic coated electrode arc gouging.",
    "Arc gouging with graphite electrode.",
    "Arc gouging with cellulosic coated electrode.",
    "Arc gouging with tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which process cannot oxidizing shielding gases be used?",
    answers: ["111",
    "135",
    "12",
    "141"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A GTAW/TIG tungsten electrode prepared to a balled end would be used to:",
    answers: ["weld stainless steel.",
    "weld carbon steel.",
    "weld magnesium.",
    "weld copper."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the air-cooled GTAW torch compared to the water-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the air-cooled torch is heavier;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon-helium mixture only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with small diameter tungsten electrode only."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the air-cooled GTAW torch compared to the water-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the air-cooled torch is bulkier;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon-helium mixture only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with small diameter tungsten electrode only."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the air-cooled GTAW torch compared to the water-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["its duty cycle is shorter;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon-helium mixture only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with small diameter tungsten electrode only."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the air-cooled GMAW torch compared to the water-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the air-cooled torch is heavier;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with CO2 gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is generally shorter."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the air-cooled GMAW torch compared to the water-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the air-cooled torch is bulkier;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with CO2 gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is generally shorter."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the air-cooled GMAW torch compared to the water-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["its duty cycle is shorter;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is used with CO2 gas only;",
    "the air-cooled torch is generally shorter."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the water-cooled GTAW torch compared to the air-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the water-cooled torch is used with argon-helium mixture only;",
    "it has more parts to give problems (cooler pump, fan, etc.);",
    "the water-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "The water-cooled torch is only used with large diameter tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the water-cooled GTAW torch compared to the air-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the water-cooled torch is used with argon-helium mixture only;",
    "it is more expensive;",
    "the water-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "The water-cooled torch is only used with large diameter tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the water-cooled GTAW torch compared to the air-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the water-cooled torch is used with argon-helium mixture only;",
    "the water-cooled torch needs more maintenance;",
    "the water-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "The water-cooled torch is only used with large diameter tungsten electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the water-cooled GMAW torch compared to the air-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the water-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "it has more parts to give problems (cooler pump, fan, etc.);",
    "the water-cooled torch is only used with CO2 gas (as the CO2 arc is hotter);",
    "the water-cooled torch is generally shorter."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the water-cooled GMAW torch compared to the air-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the water-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "it is more expensive;",
    "the water-cooled torch is only used with CO2 gas (as the CO2 arc is hotter);",
    "the water-cooled torch is generally shorter."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A disadvantage of the water-cooled GMAW torch compared to the air-cooled one is:",
    answers: ["the water-cooled torch is used with argon gas only;",
    "the water-cooled torch needs more maintenance;",
    "the water-cooled torch is only used with CO2 gas (as the CO2 arc is hotter);",
    "the water-cooled torch is generally shorter."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Air-cooled GTAW (TIG) torches have an advantage because:",
    answers: ["higher currents can be used;",
    "they are compact and less expensive;",
    "they have a longer service life (compared to water-cooled ones);",
    "a lower gas flow rate can be used."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Air-cooled GMAW (MIG/MAG) torches have an advantage because:",
    answers: ["higher currents can be used;",
    "they are compact and less expensive;",
    "they have a longer service life (compared to water-cooled ones);",
    "a lower gas flow rate can be used."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"A proper length of the arc for GTAW (TIG welding) is equal to:",
    answers: ["1 - 2 mm;",
    "2 - 3 mm;",
    "3 - 5 mm;",
    "the size (diameter) of the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What types of power sources are available for GTAW/TIG?",
    answers: ["Transformers with Constant Current type output characteristic.",
    "Transformers - Rectifiers with Constant Voltage type output characteristic.",
    "Transformers with Constant Voltage type output characteristic (for welding aluminium).",
    "Three-phase transformers (for welding aluminium)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What welding conditions would you use to weld a 120 x 250 mm patch to a 2 mm wall thick water tank that is leaking?",
    answers: ["Cellulosic type electrode (E-6010) with high current to increase productivity.",
    "Basic type electrode (E-7018) 4 mm in diameter to ensure good repair tenacity.",
    "Acid electrode, to match the basicity of water.",
    "Rutile type electrode (E-6013) with small diameter (from 1.6 to 2.4 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which safety precaution should be taken to avoid accidental arcing of tungsten electrode when not in use in GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["The torch should be always hung on an insulated holder. ",
    "The current should be reduced immediately after welding.",
    "The power source should be turned off.",
    "The arc voltage should be reduced immediately after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"\"A \"\"crater time\"\" GTAW (TIG welding) power source function allows:\"",
    answers: ["to turn off the current before the arc is extinguished;",
    "that the gas will flow after the arc is extinguished;",
    "increase current to facilitate crater refilling;",
    "to reduce current to avoid crater depression (with possible addition of filler metal)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following combinations of the current type and polarity is suitable for welding medium-carbon steel pipes with GTAW (TIG welding)?",
    answers: ["DCEP.",
    "AC with high frequency arc striking.",
    "DCEN.",
    "DCEP pulsed current."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is an advantage of the Covered Electrode Welding?",
    answers: ["The filler metal and means of protection during welding are provided by the covered electrode itself.",
    "High productivity.",
    "Low volume of gases generated in the process.",
    "Covered electrodes do not need special care."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is an advantage of the Covered Electrode Welding?",
    answers: ["High productivity.",
    "The equipment is relatively simple and inexpensive.",
    "Low volume of gases generated in the process.",
    "Covered electrodes do not need special care."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is an advantage of the Covered Electrode Welding?",
    answers: ["High productivity.",
    "Low volume of gases generated in the process.",
    "Takes up little physical space.",
    "Covered electrodes do not need special care."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What is an advantage of the Covered Electrode Welding?",
    answers: ["High productivity.",
    "Low volume of gases generated in the process.",
    "Covered electrodes do not need special care.",
    "Can be used in limited access areas."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Covered Electrode welding process:",
    answers: ["It is suitable for materials thickness above 0.5 mm.",
    "The power sources for the Covered Electrode welding process must be of the Constant Current type.",
    "The main reason for the low deposition rate of the process, compared to other arc processes, is the fact that the electrode feed is not continuous.",
    "The protection of the weld pool and of the droplets is always achieved by the slag."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Covered Electrode welding process:",
    answers: ["It is suitable for materials thickness above 0.5 mm.",
    "The main reason for the low deposition rate of the process, compared to other arc processes, is the fact that the electrode feed is not continuous.",
    "The most typical discontinuities that can be found in beads made by this welding process are porosity and slag inclusions.",
    "The protection of the weld pool and of the droplets is always achieved by the slag."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the Covered Electrode welding process:",
    answers: ["It is suitable for materials thickness above 0.5 mm.",
    "The main reason for the low deposition rate of the process, compared to other arc processes, is the fact that the electrode feed is not continuous.",
    "The protection of the weld pool and of the droplets is always achieved by the slag.",
    "It is suitable for most metals and metal alloys (carbon steel, low, medium and high alloy steels, stainless steel, cast iron, copper, nickel and their alloys)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What characteristic is typical for the pulsed MIG welding process?",
    answers: ["Metal transfer control.",
    "High welding current.",
    "Low consumption of shielding gas.",
    "Low arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"\"The risk of the electrode sticking (\"\"freezing\"\") to the plate becomes greater:\"",
    answers: ["during the striking the arc;",
    "with increasing the current pre-set value;",
    "with increasing the arc length;",
    "when welding in the flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"\"The risk of the electrode sticking (\"\"freezing\"\") to the plate becomes greater:\"",
    answers: ["with increasing the current pre-set value;",
    "with the reduction of the current pre-set value;",
    "with increasing the arc length;",
    "when welding in the flat position."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to the oxyfuel gas welding (OFW):",
    answers: ["Propane is the most used gas in the OFW, due to its high combustion power and low cost.",
    "The more oxygen in the gas mixture, the more easily reactive materials are welded together, as the reaction of metal with oxygen is exothermic.",
    "The combustion of fuel gas (e.g., acetylene) takes place only with oxygen from the atmosphere, which makes the process very economical.",
    "To achieve a reducing flame, a slightly higher flow rate of acetylene than used to obtain a neutral flame must be provided."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to the oxyfuel gas welding (OFW):",
    answers: ["Propane is the most used gas in the OFW, due to its high combustion power and low cost.",
    "The more oxygen in the gas mixture, the more easily reactive materials are welded together, as the reaction of metal with oxygen is exothermic.",
    "May or may not use filler metal.",
    "The combustion of fuel gas (e.g., acetylene) takes place only with oxygen from the atmosphere, which makes the process very economical."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What function does the preheating flame perform in oxy-cutting?",
    answers: ["It heats the material to the ignition temperature.",
    "It cleans the piece surface from the scale.",
    "It protects the cut surface from atmospheric air.",
    "It prevents the formation of metallic bridges."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What function does the preheating flame perform in oxy-cutting?",
    answers: ["It cleans the piece surface from the scale.",
    "It compensates heat losses during cutting.",
    "It protects the cut surface from atmospheric air.",
    "It prevents the formation of metallic bridges."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In case of an increase in spatter has been observed during MIG/MAG welding of steel, this could be caused, most likely by ...",
    answers: ["oscillations of the electrode wire feeding;",
    "a rapid change in the no-load voltage of the power source;",
    "an increase in the flow of shielding gas;",
    "a wrong polarity of the welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In case of an increase in spatter has been observed during MIG/MAG welding of steel, this could be caused, most likely by ...",
    answers: ["a rapid change in the no-load voltage of the power source;",
    "rapid changes in the contact tube-to-work distance;",
    "an increase in the flow of shielding gas;",
    "a wrong polarity of the welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In case of an increase in spatter has been observed during MIG/MAG welding of steel, this could be caused, most likely by ...",
    answers: ["a rapid change in the no-load voltage of the power source;",
    "a wrong polarity of the welding current.",
    "an increase in the flow of shielding gas;",
    "an effect of magnetic blow."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The colour code of the EWP electrode for TIG welding (GTAW) is:",
    answers: ["red;",
    "green;",
    "yellow;",
    "black."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is NOT a feature of MIG/MAG welding with spray-type metal transfer:",
    answers: ["low spatter;",
    "smooth weld surface without scales;",
    "welding in all positions;",
    "high welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is NOT a feature of MIG/MAG welding with short-circuiting metal transfer:",
    answers: ["spatter;",
    "smooth weld surface without scales;",
    "welding in all positions;",
    "low welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Gas mixtures are used in MIG/MAG welding to:",
    answers: ["provide alloying elements for the weld pool;",
    "to cool down the welding torch;",
    "protect weld pool from atmospheric contamination and to improve arc stability;",
    "cool the weld region."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In arc welding, the choice of current value mainly depends on:",
    answers: ["the cleanliness of the work surface;",
    "the type and thickness of the parts to be welded;",
    "the workpiece preheat temperature;",
    "the power source used."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which contaminant below should be avoided at all costs in the connections of oxygen hoses in the oxyfuel gas cutting process?",
    answers: ["Water, as the hydrogen in the water molecule can explode.",
    "Oil or grease, as it can cause an explosion.",
    "Dust, as it can clog the hoses.",
    "Rust, as it hampers tightening the connections."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"To increase the amount of heat produced by the flame you would change:",
    answers: ["the type of gas and/or its flow rate;",
    "the torch type;",
    "the size of the torch's hose;",
    "the length of the flame."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a too low welding current;",
    "a very short arc length;",
    "a very high gas flow;",
    "a too low arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a very short arc length;",
    "a too high welding current;",
    "a very high gas flow;",
    "a too low arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a very short arc length;",
    "a very high gas flow;",
    "a wrong electrode selection;",
    "a too low arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a very short arc length;",
    "a very high gas flow;",
    "a too low arc voltage;",
    "the electrode tip contamination."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a too low gas flow rate;",
    "a very short arc length;",
    "a too low arc voltage;",
    "a very high gas flow."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a very short arc length;",
    "a wrong electrode tip preparation (crosswise grinding);",
    "a wrong electrode tip preparation (lengthwise grinding);",
    "a very high gas flow."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["the positive electrode polarity used;",
    "the negative electrode polarity used;",
    "a wrong electrode tip preparation (lengthwise grinding);",
    "a very high gas flow."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a very short arc length;",
    "a too low arc voltage;",
    "a too small electrode sharpening angle;",
    "a too large electrode sharpening angle."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"An unstable or erratic arc when using GTAW/TIG welding can be caused by:",
    answers: ["a too small electrode sharpening angle;",
    "a contamination of the base metal (paint, grease, oil, scale);",
    "a very short arc length;",
    "a too low arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"For what situation is the use of basic coated electrodes preferable?",
    answers: ["When a smooth bead surface is required.",
    "When better mechanical properties, including impact resistance, are required.",
    "For welding in vertical downward position.",
    "If high penetration is required."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting the wire feed speed in the GMAW (MIG/MAG) process?",
    answers: ["Shielding gas type used.",
    "The required arc length.",
    "Base metal thickness.",
    "Welding technique (pulling or pushing/backhand or forehand)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting the wire feed speed in the GMAW (MIG/MAG) process?",
    answers: ["Shielding gas type used.",
    "The required arc length.",
    "Electrode wire diameter.",
    "Welding technique (pulling or pushing/backhand or forehand)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following factors should be considered when selecting the wire feed speed in the GMAW (MIG/MAG) process?",
    answers: ["Shielding gas type used.",
    "The required arc length.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Welding technique (pulling or pushing/backhand or forehand)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In conventional MIG/MAG welding, the welding current is regulated:",
    answers: ["by adjusting the pressure of the wire rollers;",
    "by adjusting the wire feed speed;",
    "by the contact tube-to-work distance;",
    "by adjusting the arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which factor below determines the size of the torch tip for cutting carbon steel sheets with the oxy-acetylene process?",
    answers: ["The carbon content of the steel.",
    "The desired cut (bleed) width.",
    "The length to be cut.",
    "The thickness of the plate."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statement regarding the output static characteristic of the arc welding power source (V-A-C).",
    answers: ["The V-A-C expresses the dependence of voltage output on current output intensity during rapidly changing welding conditions.",
    "The V-A-C expresses the dependence of the voltage output on the current output intensity under steady-state conditions.",
    "The best power source type for MIG/MAG (GMAW) welding is a constant current V-A-C type.",
    "The best type of power source for TIG welding is a constant voltage V-A-C type."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In which case would basic covered electrodes be used preferentially?",
    answers: ["If smooth weld surfaces are required.",
    "When the weld requires good H2 control and/or impact strength and/or fatigue strength.",
    "If there is a need to use alternating current.",
    "If, for example, high deposition rates are required."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The coating of a covered electrode performs one of the following functions. Which one?",
    answers: ["It reduces residual welding stresses.",
    "It provides chemical compounds for slag formation.",
    "It increases the melting rate of the electrode rod (core).",
    "It protects the electrode core against contamination by atmospheric gases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The coating of a covered electrode performs one of the following functions. Which one?",
    answers: ["It facilitates ionization and promotes arc stabilization.",
    "It reduces residual welding stresses.",
    "It increases the melting rate of the electrode rod (core).",
    "It protects the electrode core against contamination by atmospheric gases."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The coating of a covered electrode performs one of the following functions. Which one?",
    answers: ["It reduces residual welding stresses.",
    "It provides alloying elements to control the chemical composition of the weld metal.",
    "It increases the melting rate of the electrode rod (core).",
    "It protects the electrode core against contamination by atmospheric gases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The coating of a covered electrode performs one of the following functions. Which one?",
    answers: ["It reduces residual welding stresses.",
    "It provides chemical elements for deoxidation of the weld pool.",
    "It increases the melting rate of the electrode rod (core).",
    "It protects the electrode core against contamination by atmospheric gases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"To strike the arc in TIG welding…",
    answers: ["a high no-load voltage can be used, which allows striking the arc without touching the surface of the workpiece;",
    "\"a special technique known as \"\"Lift Arc\"\" or \"\"Touch and Pull\"\" (or similar) can be used;\"",
    "\"a special technique known as \"\"Push - Pull\"\" can be used;\"",
    "\"a special technique known as \"\"Soft Start\"\" (slow approach of the electrode) can be used.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"To strike the arc in TIG welding…",
    answers: ["a high no-load voltage can be used, which allows striking the arc without touching the surface of the workpiece.",
    "\"a special technique known as \"\"Push - Pull\"\" can be used;\"",
    "high frequency and high voltage can be used;",
    "\"a special technique known as \"\"Soft Start\"\" (slow approach of the electrode) can be used.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0"},
    {
    question:"What can cause weld cracks in arc welding?",
    answers: ["A highly restrained joint assembly.",
    "A too short arc.",
    "Too slow cooling.",
    "Incorrect handling of the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What can cause weld cracks in arc welding?",
    answers: ["Dirty joint borders.",
    "A too short arc.",
    "Too slow cooling.",
    "Incorrect handling of the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What can cause weld cracks in arc welding?",
    answers: ["Very fast cooling.",
    "A too short arc.",
    "Too slow cooling.",
    "Incorrect handling of the electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the fused zone?",
    answers: ["Region of the welded joint where, during welding, the metal was in a liquid state.",
    "Region in which the weld bead is widest.",
    "Region on the axis of the welded joint.",
    "Region of the welded joint that is in the liquid state."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What kind of defect can possibly occur due to a high hydrogen content in the coating of covered electrodes when welding low-alloy steels?",
    answers: ["Hot cracking in the weld metal.",
    "Cold cracking in the heat affected zone.",
    "Porosity in the weld metal.",
    "Development of martensite in the HAZ."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which are the main alloying elements in X2CrNi18-10 steel (as per EN code)?",
    answers: ["18 % nickel and 10 % chromium.",
    "18 % chromium and 10 % nickel.",
    "18 % chromium and 10 % iron.",
    "1,8% chromium and 1 % nickel."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"\"Which of the following describes \"\"Buttering\"\"?\"",
    answers: ["Lining the side of a prepared joint with weld.",
    "Weaving back and forth across a prepared joint.",
    "The cover pass of a prepared joint.",
    "The fill pass of a prepared joint."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following shielding gases will result in increased penetration when TIG welding copper?",
    answers: ["Ar.",
    "Ar + 25%He. ",
    "Ar + 75%He.",
    "Ar + 2%CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Assuming that the plate thickness and the other chemical elements of their composition are equal, which of the following four steels has good weldability?",
    answers: ["C = 0,40% and Mn = 1,20%.",
    "C = 0,45% and Mn = 0,90%.",
    "C = 0,45% and Mn = 1,20%.",
    "C = 0,08% and Mn = 0,90%."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Assuming that the plate thickness and the other chemical elements of their composition are equal, which of the following four steels has good weldability?",
    answers: ["C = 0,40% and Mn = 1,20%.",
    "C = 0,45% and Mn = 0,90%.",
    "C = 0,45% and Mn = 1,20%.",
    "C = 0,08% and Mn = 1,60%."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which statement regarding welding of aluminium is correct?",
    answers: ["When welding thick plates made of aluminium, pre-heating may be required due to its higher thermal conductivity.",
    "When welding aluminium, pre-heating is not recommended, as it can generate fragile microstructures in the ZAC.",
    "High thermal conductivity of aluminium makes preheating unnecessary, as the heat from the weld pool spreads through the ZAC almost instantly.",
    "When welding aluminium, pre-heating is not recommended, as it softens aluminium, which can cause defects such as excessive penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The back stepping technique:",
    answers: ["allows to increase penetration;",
    "serves as a type of stress relieving and also reduces the distortion;",
    "allows to avoid the lack of fusion;",
    "allows to increase the deposition rate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the main objectives of heat treatment of the welded joint is:",
    answers: ["stress relieving;",
    "reduction of the heat affected zone (HAZ) size;",
    "elimination of excessive oxidation zones;",
    "reduction of deformation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Stainless steels can be welded by:",
    answers: ["Oxy-Fuel welding (OFW), MMA(SMAW) and TIG(GTAW);",
    "Oxy-Fuel welding (OFW), MMA(SMAW) and MIG/MAG(GMAW);",
    "MMA(SMAW), TIG(GTAW) and MIG/MAG(GMAW);",
    "Oxy-Fuel welding (OFW), MMA(SMAW) and SAW."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Are there any special precautions to minimise distortion in welding of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Yes, the distance between the tack welds shall be relatively long compared to non-alloy steel.",
    "No, you can proceed as for welding of non-alloy steels.",
    "No, because stainless steels are not sensitive to distortion (due to high ductility).",
    "Yes, the tack welds shall be put at a shorter distance than for non-alloy steel."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The most common type of covered electrodes for welding of stainless steels are:",
    answers: ["acid type electrode;",
    "basic type electrode;",
    "cellulosic type electrode;",
    "rutile type electrode."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which shielding gas is most suitable for MIG/MAG-welding (GMAW) of austenitic stainless steel?",
    answers: ["Pure argon.",
    "Gas mixture argon + helium.",
    "Gas mixture argon+2%CO2.",
    "CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which backing gas should be used for TIG-welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["Argon.",
    "Gas mixture argon + oxygen.",
    "Gas mixture nitrogen + hydrogen.",
    "CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cleaning of joint preparations prior to welding of aluminium:",
    answers: ["shall be done within 48 hours prior to welding;",
    "shall be done at least 24 hours prior to welding;",
    "shall be done immediately before welding;",
    "Depends on welding process to be used."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When the heat input decreases, then the need for preheating:",
    answers: ["increases to compensate the reduction of the heat income;",
    "decreases to syntonize with the reduction of the heat income;",
    "increases or decreases depending on the workpiece thickness;",
    "stays as it is because the heat input does not affect the need for preheating."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The heat affected zone (HAZ) is:",
    answers: ["the part of the parent metal, which has been melted during welding;",
    "the part of the parent metal, on which the welding has caused changes in the microstructure;",
    "the part of the parent metal, on which the welding has caused changes in the macrostructure;",
    "the part of the parent metal which suffered heating during welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which backing gas should be used for TIG-welding of austenitic stainless steel pipes?",
    answers: ["Argon + CO2.",
    "Pure argon or gas mixture nitrogen-hydrogen.",
    "Gas mixture helium + hydrogen.",
    "Gas mixture nitrogen + CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which imperfections can cause corrosion in stainless steel welded joints?",
    answers: ["Tungsten inclusions.",
    "Internal porosity.",
    "Reinforcement.",
    "Spatter."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which imperfections can cause corrosion in stainless steel welded joints?",
    answers: ["Tungsten inclusions.",
    "Internal porosity.",
    "Reinforcement.",
    "Stray arc marks."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which imperfections can cause corrosion in stainless steel welded joints?",
    answers: ["Tungsten inclusions.",
    "Internal porosity.",
    "Reinforcement.",
    "Grinding marks."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is it important to store aluminium filler materials in dry conditions before use?",
    answers: ["Because moisture can cause an excessive oxidation.",
    "Because moisture can cause a corrosion.",
    "Because moisture is taken in outer oxide-layer of the filler metal.",
    "Because moisture can cause arc instabilities."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why it is necessary to remove the thick oxide layer from the joint preparation (using a stainless-steel brush) prior to welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["Due to the high heat required to weld through a thick oxide layer, there is a risk of a “burn through”.",
    "The arc does not destroy the oxide layer.",
    "A thick oxide layer reduces the deposition rate. ",
    "A thick oxide layer can reflect the arc. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why it is necessary to remove the thick oxide layer from the joint preparation (using a stainless-steel brush) prior to welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["To avoid oxide inclusions in the weld metal.",
    "The arc does not destroy the oxide layer.",
    "A thick oxide layer reduces the deposition rate. ",
    "A thick oxide layer can reflect the arc. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Why it is necessary to remove the thick oxide layer from the joint preparation (using a stainless-steel brush) prior to welding of aluminium?",
    answers: ["A thick oxide layer, which acts as an insulator, can cause arc start problems.",
    "The arc does not destroy the oxide layer.",
    "A thick oxide layer reduces the deposition rate. ",
    "A thick oxide layer can reflect the arc. "],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When the carbon equivalent increases, then the need for:",
    answers: ["preheating decreases;",
    "preheating also increases;",
    "post-heating decreases;",
    "PWHT decreases."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which polarity do you choose for MIG/MAG welding of stainless steels?",
    answers: ["Unlike carbon steels, the positive electrode polarity.",
    "Unlike carbon steels, the negative electrode polarity.",
    "The same as in the case of carbon steels, the negative electrode polarity.",
    "The same as in the case of carbon steels, the positive electrode polarity."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Compared to non-alloy steels austenitic stainless steels have a higher:",
    answers: ["thermal conductivity;",
    "thermal expansion;",
    "electrical conductivity;",
    "ferrite content."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Austenitic stainless steel shall be welded with a lower (than for non-alloy steel) heat input:",
    answers: ["to reduce distortion;",
    "to avoid possible burning out of the alloying elements;",
    "to reduce possible losses of heat generated by the arc;",
    "for better control of the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Austenitic stainless steel shall be welded with a lower (than for non-alloy steel) heat input:",
    answers: ["to minimize risk for corrosion;",
    "to avoid possible burning out of the alloying elements;",
    "to reduce possible losses of heat generated by the arc;",
    "for better control of the weld pool."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Stainless steels have a good corrosion resistance in an oxidizing atmosphere due to:",
    answers: ["a low carbon content;",
    "a chromium oxide protective layer;",
    "a high nickel content;",
    "a correct balance between nickel and ferrite."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The recommended electrode inclination for TIG welding (GTAW) using a filler rod is:",
    answers: ["5 degrees to 20 degrees forehand (push);",
    "5 degrees to 20 degrees backhand (drag);",
    "25 degrees to 45 degrees forehand (push);",
    "25 degrees to 45 degrees backhand (drag);"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Most austenitic stainless steels:",
    answers: ["will normally require some type of preheat and post heat;",
    "will normally require some type of interpass heat;",
    "do not normally require any preheat or postheat;",
    "do not have good weldability."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Acetylene is a good choice for gas welding and cutting because: ",
    answers: ["it produces the highest volume of heat;",
    "it produces the highest temperature and concentrated heat;",
    "it is cheap;",
    "it is easy to be handled."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following fuel gases would be the most efficient for preheat? ",
    answers: ["Acetylene.",
    "Natural gas.",
    "Propane.",
    "LGP"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The gas welding of a thick aluminium plate requires a larger tip than for gas welding mild steel plate of the same thickness because aluminium has a:",
    answers: ["reflective surface;",
    "thick heat resistant oxide film on its surface;",
    "some kind of surface treatment such as anodising, which needs more heat to be remelted;",
    "higher thermal conductivity."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is considered when determining the need for post heating of a weld? ",
    answers: ["Thickness of material.",
    "Welding process used.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is considered to determine post heating of a weld? ",
    answers: ["Carbon content.",
    "Welding process used.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is considered to determine post heating of a weld? ",
    answers: ["Prior heat treatment.",
    "Welding process used.",
    "Welding position.",
    "Arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding mild steel with the MIG/MAG welding (GMAW) process, what shielding gas gives you the deepest penetration?",
    answers: ["Argon.",
    "Helium.",
    "Ar + CO2 mixture.",
    "CO2."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these factors does NOT affect the structure of a chosen point in the heat affected zone in arc welding?",
    answers: ["The maximum temperature to which the point is heated.",
    "The chemical composition of the filler material.",
    "The chemical composition of the parent metal.",
    "The cooling rate."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What may be one of the reasons for cold cracking in the HAZ of an unalloyed or fine-grained steel weldment?",
    answers: ["Presence of diffusible hydrogen.",
    "Low-temperature operation.",
    "Too high preheating.",
    "An increased heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Stainless steels are corrosion resistant:",
    answers: ["due to fine-grained austenitic structure;",
    "due to insoluble chromium oxides present at the surface;",
    "because these steels are not magnetic, therefore they cannot form galvanic cells;",
    "because chromium does not form oxides."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The use of the basic coating electrode is recommended for welding:",
    answers: ["small thicknesses;",
    "assemblies with low level of the stiffness;",
    "pipe circumferential welds;",
    "steels of unknown chemical composition."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"A deposited metal suitable for dynamically loaded joint must have a high:",
    answers: ["hardness;",
    "tensile strength;",
    "ductility;",
    "yield strength."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What weld type can be applied to a lap joint?",
    answers: ["Projection welding weld.",
    "Butt single V weld.",
    "Butt single U weld.",
    "Butt square weld."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What weld type can be applied to a lap joint?",
    answers: ["\"Butt \"\"K\"\" weld.\"",
    "Seam weld.",
    "Butt single U weld.",
    "Butt square weld."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What weld type can be applied to a lap joint?",
    answers: ["\"Butt \"\"K\"\" weld.\"",
    "Butt single V weld.",
    "Plug or slot welds.",
    "Butt square weld."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What weld type can be applied to a lap joint?",
    answers: ["\"Butt \"\"K\"\" weld.\"",
    "Butt single V weld.",
    "Butt single U weld.",
    "Fillet welds."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The fillet weld strength is calculated using:",
    answers: ["the dimension of its cross section area;",
    "the dimension of its longitudinal effective area;",
    "the reinforcement + penetration;",
    "the length of the hypotenuse of the triangle inscribed within its cross section."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Notches in a metal structure should be avoided as:",
    answers: ["they facilitate crack propagation under static loading;",
    "they reduce the yield strength of the material;",
    "they worsen the aesthetics of structures;",
    "they facilitate the nucleation of cracks under cyclic/dynamic loading."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the fillet weld it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["For equivalent strengths, continuous fillet welds use less filler metal than intermittent fillet welds;",
    "For equivalent strengths, concave fillet welds have a smaller leg size compared to convex fillet welds;",
    "For equivalent strengths, convex fillet welds have a smaller leg size compared to concave fillet welds thanks to the contribution of reinforcement to strength;",
    "The mechanical strength of the convex fillet weld can always be increased by greater reinforcements."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the fillet weld it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["For equivalent strengths, concave fillet welds have the same leg size as convex fillet welds;",
    "For equivalent strengths, concave fillet welds have a smaller leg size compared to convex fillet welds;",
    "For equivalent strengths, convex fillet welds have a smaller leg size compared to concave fillet welds thanks to the contribution of reinforcement to strength;",
    "The mechanical strength of the convex fillet weld can always be increased by greater reinforcements."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What has to be taken into account by the designer when selecting the type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Joints with a greater volume of deposited metal are more preferable;",
    "Corner joints are less prone to deformation than butt joints;",
    "The application of high-strength steels makes it possible to carry out welds with partial penetration;",
    "Accessibility for joint inspection with NDT."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What has to be taken into account by the designer when selecting the type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Joints with a greater volume of deposited metal are more preferable;",
    "Corner joints are less prone to deformation than butt joints;",
    "The application of high-strength steels makes it possible to carry out welds with partial penetration;",
    "Joint types that require less deposited metal are more preferable."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What has to be taken into account by the designer when selecting the type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Joints with a greater volume of deposited metal are more preferable;",
    "Corner joints are less prone to deformation than butt joints;",
    "The application of high-strength steels makes it possible to carry out welds with partial penetration;",
    "For thick plates, grooves from both sides are recommended rather than just from one side."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What has to be taken into account by the designer when selecting the type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Joints with a greater volume of deposited metal are more preferable;",
    "Corner joints are less prone to deformation than butt joints;",
    "The application of high-strength steels makes it possible to carry out welds with partial penetration;",
    "Joint type and groove design influence manufacturing costs."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What has to be taken into account by the designer when selecting the type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Joints with a greater volume of deposited metal are more preferable;",
    "Corner joints are less prone to deformation than butt joints;",
    "The application of high-strength steels makes it possible to carry out welds with partial penetration;",
    "Joint type and groove design influence distortion."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What has to be taken into account by the designer when selecting the type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["Joints with a greater volume of deposited metal are more preferable;",
    "Corner joints are less prone to deformation than butt joints;",
    "The application of high-strength steels makes it possible to carry out welds with partial penetration;",
    "Residual stresses depend on the type of joint and groove, as well as on the volume of weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"What has to be taken into account by the designer when selecting the type of welded joint?",
    answers: ["The type of joint and groove design has influence upon distortion.",
    "The type of joint and groove design has no influence upon residual stresses.",
    "It is recommended whenever possible to select the type of joint that requires the greatest volume of deposited metal (higher strength!).",
    "Concave welds are always preferable to convex ones."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In order to calculate the design throat thickness of a fillet welded T joint, you would multiply the leg length by:",
    answers: ["0.5;",
    "0.6;",
    "0.7;",
    "0.9."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which different radiation types are generated during arc welding?",
    answers: ["Ultra violet (UV), X-rays and visible light radiation.",
    "Heat radiation, visible light radiation and gamma radiation.",
    "Ultra violet (UV), infra-red (IR) and visible light radiation.",
    "Infra-red and heat radiation."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"If the content of the carbon monoxide in the breathing area is high, it may cause:",
    answers: ["a risk for suffocating;",
    "the asthma;",
    "the lung cancer;",
    "a risk for intoxication."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which material is more prone to distortion?",
    answers: ["Carbon steel.",
    "Stainless steel.",
    "Aluminium.",
    "Copper."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The distortion can be minimized by:",
    answers: ["using a skeleton frame with clamps;",
    "a general postheat of the joint areas;",
    "increasing the number of runs;",
    "increasing the heat input."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"\"The most important reason to use the \"\"back-step\"\" welding technique is to:\"",
    answers: ["speed up the welding operation;",
    "reduce the level of distortion;",
    "increase the mechanical strength of the weld;",
    "obtain grain refinement."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Weld imperfection, which can, with high probability, lead to a failure of the welded structure, is:",
    answers: ["lack of fusion;",
    "weld reinforcement; ",
    "excessive throat;",
    "excessive fillet weld asymmetry."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The weld discontinuity that originates at the weld root, due to a lack of deposition or fusion of the parent metal, is called:",
    answers: ["Undercut.",
    "Crack.",
    "Porosity.",
    "Lack of penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"A welder qualified for welding carbon steel with the MIG short-circuiting process can ...",
    answers: ["weld with any other welding process as he was qualified for the most difficult one.",
    "weld any other material with MIG/MAG welding;",
    "weld only carbon steel and only with short-circuiting MIG/MAG welding process;",
    "use MIG/MAG welding either with spray or short-circuiting metal transfer, because what matters is the MIG/MAG process the welder is qualified for."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is a qualified welder?",
    answers: ["A welding professional with a work portfolio.",
    "A welding professional who has undergone in-company training.",
    "A welding professional with more than 5 years of experience proven by work portfolio.",
    "A welding professional who has undergone an assessment to prove their skill in a given welding process."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these alternatives would provide the best respiratory protection from toxic fumes such as cadmium or lead? ",
    answers: ["Self-contained breathing apparatus or air supplied respirator.",
    "Dust mask.",
    "Open windows and doors.",
    "Welder's head position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Most accidents are caused by:",
    answers: ["worn out machinery;",
    "human error;",
    "faulty engineering;",
    "mechanical failure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Why is it best to push a cart with gas cylinders forward, rather than pull it backward?",
    answers: ["It is easier on the back.",
    "To avoid crushing feet.",
    "So, the hoses are behind the wheels.",
    "To see possible hazards."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Compared to non-alloy steel the sensitivity for distortion of stainless steel is:",
    answers: ["Higher;",
    "Lower;",
    "Approximately the same;",
    "Higher or lower depending on the stainless steel type."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Compared to carbon steel the sensitivity for distortion of aluminium is:",
    answers: ["Higher;",
    "Lower;",
    "Approximately the same;",
    "Higher or lower depending on the aluminium alloy type."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which scale numbers for a welding filter according to EN 169 are normally used for TIG-welding?",
    answers: ["1 a 3",
    "3 a 7",
    "8 a 14",
    "14 a 16"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which scale numbers for a welding filter according to EN 169 are normally used for MAG-welding (GMAW)?",
    answers: ["1 a 3",
    "3 a 7",
    "8 a 14",
    "14 a 16"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following processes would require the darkest filter lens?",
    answers: ["Oxy-acetylene welding.",
    "MMA (SMAW) welding, electrode diameter of 4 mm.",
    "MMA (SMAW) welding, electrode diameter of 2.5 mm.",
    "Oxy-acetylene cutting of 20 mm thick metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following processes would require the darkest filter lens?",
    answers: ["Oxy-acetylene welding.",
    "MMA (SMAW) welding, electrode diameter of 2.5 mm.",
    "Arc air gouging.",
    "Oxy-acetylene cutting of 20 mm thick metal."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following processes would require the lightest filter lens?",
    answers: ["Oxy-acetylene welding.",
    "MMA (SMAW) welding, electrode diameter of 4 mm.",
    "MMA (SMAW) welding, electrode diameter of 2.5 mm.",
    "Oxy-acetylene cutting of 20 mm thick metal."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following processes would require the lightest filter lens?",
    answers: ["Arc air gouging.",
    "MMA (SMAW) welding, electrode diameter of 4 mm.",
    "MMA (SMAW) welding, electrode diameter of 2.5 mm.",
    "Oxy-acetylene cutting of 20 mm thick metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Inspection of welded joints must be carried out:",
    answers: ["After welding only;",
    "Before and after welding;",
    "During and after welding;",
    "Before, during and after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"You are thinking of building your career in welding. What do you think, who knows the welding technology better, a welding engineer or a welding inspector?",
    answers: ["The inspector, as he is the one who inspects the welding process, issues and signs the final welding quality report.",
    "The inspector, as he is the one who inspects the welding process and advises the engineer how to do the welding better.",
    "The engineer, because he/she is the one who selects the welding process, equipment, consumables and organizes the manufacturing process.",
    "The engineer, as he/she is the one who selects the welding process, equipment and consumables, organizes the manufacturing process and advises the inspector on his tasks."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"In arc welding with gas protection, the REAL value of the gas flow rate is measured by:",
    answers: ["a rotameter installed after the pressure regulator;",
    "a pressure gauge installed after the pressure regulator;",
    "a flowmeter installed after the solenoid valve;",
    "a nozzle flowmeter – rotameter placed at the torch nozzle."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"According to ISO 9606, the welder's qualification must be revalidated if:",
    answers: ["the period of 2 years is exceeded;",
    "it is required by the Welding Inspector;",
    "he is not engaged in welding jobs for more than three months;",
    "the welder changes company."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the weld bead imperfections is considered to be external?",
    answers: ["Lack of penetration on the root on a X-butt weld.",
    "Lack of side wall fusion.",
    "Lack of penetration in the butt weld without edge preparation with welding on both sides.",
    "Lack of penetration on the root on a V-butt weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the weld bead imperfections is considered to be external?",
    answers: ["Lack of penetration on the root on a X-butt weld.",
    "Lack of side wall fusion.",
    "Lack of penetration in the butt weld without edge preparation with welding on both sides.",
    "Undercut."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the weld bead imperfections is considered to be external?",
    answers: ["Lack of penetration on the root on a X-butt weld.",
    "Lack of side wall fusion. ",
    "Lack of penetration in the butt weld without edge preparation with welding on both sides.",
    "Surface Pores."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these processes is recognized as the one with the highest deposition efficiency in relation to the others presented?",
    answers: ["GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "SAW.",
    "Short-circuiting GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    "SMAW (MMA welding)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding welding fumes, the following statement is correct:",
    answers: ["The amount of fumes generated and the concentrations of toxic substances depend on the welding method used.",
    "The particles that make up the welding fumes, although small, are not remained in suspension for a long period, so the protection must be concentrated only in the region close to the welder.",
    "Welding processes with gas shielding (MIG/MAG, TIG) do not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health, unlike the welding with Covered and Tubular Electrodes.",
    "Among all welding processes, the only TIG process does not produce fumes that are harmful to the welder's health."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is true about welding in confined spaces?",
    answers: ["Only MIG (not MAG) welding should be used.",
    "A fan is necessary to circulate the air in the confined space.",
    "If proper ventilation is not available, only stay in the vessel for 5 minutes at a time.",
    "Ensure the gas cylinders are positioned so that the gas can be turned off without leaving the space."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is true about welding in confined spaces?",
    answers: ["Only MIG (not MAG) welding should be used.",
    "A fan is necessary to circulate the air in the confined space.",
    "If proper ventilation is not available, you must use an air purifying respirator.",
    "Inert gasses are very dangerous."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is true about welding in confined spaces?",
    answers: ["Only MIG (not MAG) welding should be used.",
    "A fan is necessary to circulate the air in the confined space.",
    "If proper ventilation is not available, only stay in the vessel for 5 minutes at a time.",
    "You can pass out in as little as seven seconds and die."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is true about welding in confined spaces?",
    answers: ["Only MIG (not MAG) welding should be used.",
    "A fan is necessary to circulate the air in the confined space.",
    "If proper ventilation is not available, only stay in the vessel for 5 minutes at a time.",
    "If proper ventilation is not available, you must wear an air supplied purifier."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following is true about welding in confined spaces?",
    answers: ["Only MIG (not MAG) welding should be used.",
    "A fan is necessary to circulate the air in the confined space.",
    "If proper ventilation is not available, only stay in the vessel for 5 minutes at a time.",
    "Always have an assistant outside the confined space to monitor the operation."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"}
];